Industrial civil engineer from UTFSM, with five years of experience in business intelligence and data analytics. I have dexterity applying machine learning and data science techniques. I have experience developing projects associated with the processes of generation key business information. I am characterized by being a creative, curious, autonomous, proactive, responsible, empathetic and insightful leader. I am passionate about teamwork, programming, strategy, odds, and statistics.

Experiencia

I. Data Scientist | Walmart Chile | Sep 2020 – Dic 2020

Responsibilities: Perform predictive and / or prescriptive analysis through information modeling, using mathematical, statistical methods and / or data science techniques, optimizing data flow through the creation of data mining architectures, models and prototypes, reports and analysis methodologies based on Research and application of existing and emerging knowledge, theories, techniques and principles, always ensuring information security, providing business recommendations, providing solutions to problems of various levels of complexity, always following the guidelines, regulations and objectives of Walmart Chile and its subsidiaries.

Main achievements: Create various dashboards with the main KPIs that allowed to determine how the claims associated with the company's digital operation evolved, for example, using the Dremio and Redash tools.

II. Especialista control de riesgo | BancoEstado Microempresas | Mzo 2017 – Ene 2019

Responsibilities: Generation diagnoses of the evolution of the risk of the balances associated with clients throughout the country grouped according to office, segments and product. These diagnoses were presented to the branchs management who are responsible for managing the risk.

Responsible for creating and updating analytical bases used to generate monthly reports the risk evolution of pre-approved, semi-pre-approved and mortgage products. These reports was sented to entire risk area.

Main achievement: Develop a mathematical model to determine monthly how many new clients have to be financed by each offices to reach the goal determined by the management by the year 2021. To do this, I modeled the factors that decreased clients such as default, full payment before calendar, and payment according to calendar. In addition, I determined the sensibility of the result against each factor, this was used to define the strategy to minimize the decrease of customers.

III. Ingeniero de inteligencia de negocios | TrioGroup | Ene 2013 – May 2015

Responsibilities: Make a model of segmentation and classification of clients to apply CRM strategy focused on build customer loyalty. Responsible for analyzing the databases generated in SAP and controlling the main KPIs created from them. Also, it participated monthly in the creation of the balance sheet, providing the information on production costs.

Education

- I. Ingeniería Civil Industrial | U. T. Federico Santa María | Titulado (Mzo 2008 Myo 2014)
- II. Diploma inteligencia de negocios | Universidad de Chile | Aprobado (Ago 2015 Ene 2016)

Certifications

- I. Deep Learning | IBM | Oct 2019
- II. Data Science | IBM | Abr 2020

Technical skills

Softwares / Plataformas	Nivel de manejo		
	Mdo	Avd	Exp
Excel			\times
Microsoft SQL Server		\times	
Dremio / Redash		\times	
SAS / Rapidminer			
Power BI / Tableau			
IBM Watson Studio			
Keras / Tensorflow			

Lenguajes de programación	Nivel de manejo		
	Mdo	Avd	Exp
SQL			\times
Python		\times	
R			

Mdo: Medio | Avd: Avanzado | Exp: Experto.

Courses

- I. Machine Learning with Python | IBM
- III. Data visualization with Python | IBM
- V. Deep Learning with Tensorflow | IBM
- VII. Deep Learning with Python and Pytorch | IBM
- IX. Deep Learning Fundamentals with Keras IBM
- XI. Joining Data in PostgreSQL | Datacamp
- XIII. Data Analysis and statistical inference | Datacamp
- XV. Credit Risk Modeling in R | Datacamp

- II. Data Analysis with Python | IBM
- IV. Open Source tools for Data Science | IBM
- VI. Using GPU to Scale and Speed -up DL | IBM
- VIII. Python for Data Science and AI | IBM
- X. Databases and SQL for Data Science | IBM
- XII. Data Science Methodology | IBM
- XIV. R for SAS, SPSS and STATA Users | Datacamp
- XVI. SQL for Exloratory Data Analysis | Datacamp